NATHAN CHAN

SOFTWARE PROGRAMMER

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Hard-working Computer Science major currently attending James Madison University, with 7 months of work experience. Aiming to leverage a proven knowledge of computer aided engineering skills to successfully fill the Software Programmer role at your company. Frequently praised as adaptable by my peers, I can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TECHNICAL SOFTWARE PROGRAMMING INTERN

Verisign, Reston, VA / May 2019 - Present

- Developed automated code for my team that eliminated meticulous manual work.
- Investigated mySQL, Webhooks in GitHub, Hadoop, Ansible, Docker, Python, and Jenkins.
- Used Jenkins and Python to automate multiple jobs to validate Hadoop clusters and mySQL databases.
- Created my own docker image and used it to run my test environment.
- Participated in sprints, scrums, demos, and other team meetings offering my opinions and perspectives.
- Organized a team outing for interns and young professionals for more than 30 participants.

TECHNICAL SOFTWARE PROGRAMMING INTERN

Verisign, Reston, VA / May 2018 - Aug 2018

- Automated code for the OpenStack team.
- Investigated Python, JSON, API, httpd, flask, OpenDaylight, and curl when evaluating tools for project.
- Used Python, JSON, and API to retrieve, analyze, and update to a website in the most effective manner.
- Presented summer project to large audience including executives explaining how it worked and the significance of it.
- Learned to effectively prep for presentation by accounting for issues day of and thinking of possible questions.

DATA ENTRY CLERK

Campaign Mail and Data, Tysons Corner, VA / May 2016 - Aug 2016

• Learned to type quickly without sacrificing accuracy.

- usnathanchan@gmail.com
- (703) 789-5465
- 3272 Pony Ridge Way Oakton, VA, 22124

EDUCATION

JAMES MADISON UNIVERSITY

Harrisonburg, VA

B.S. Computer Science Candidate (Expected graduation May 2020)

Relevant Coursework

- CS 347 Web-Based Information Systems
- CS 354 Introduction to Autonomous Robotics.
- CS 430 Programming Languages.

Extracurricular Activities

- IMU Men's Vollevball
- VSA Vietnamese
 Student Association

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Java

C

Python

Unix

Git

Linux

Ansible Apache

. Jenkins

Hadoop

mySQL